cbq.qa 2012-08-04

# Commercial Bank of Qatar - Inspired by Qatar - Profile

| 

Your privacy is important to Commercialbank. This statement discloses the information practices for Commercialbank Web sites, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how the information is used, and with whom the information is shared.

We have implemented these practices for the Commercialbank website (www.cbq.com.qa). We have instructed our web-masters to include information on these privacy practices wherever personal information is collected on a Commercialbank Website.  
 _  
Personal information_  
In general, you can visit Commercialbank on the Web without telling us who you are and without revealing any information about yourself. There are times, however, when we or our partners may need information from you.

You may choose to give us personal information, such as your name and address or e-mail id that may be needed, for example, to correspond with you, to process an order or to provide you with a subscription. It is our intent to let you know how we will use such information before we collect it from you on the Internet. We provide this information through the PRIVACY link, which is presented wherever personal information is collected. If you tell us that you do not want us to use this information as basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes.

 _Information security and quality_  
We intend to protect the quality and integrity of your personally identifiable information. We are implementing appropriate technical and organizational measures, such as using encryption for transmission of credit card numbers, to help us keep your information secure, accurate, current, and complete.

We will make a sincere effort to respond in a timely manner to your requests to correct inaccuracies in your personal information. To correct inaccuracies in your personal information please return the message containing the inaccuracies to the sender with details of the correction requested.

 _Online advertising_  
Commercialbank has certain companies help us deliver our banner ads and other online communications. These companies may collect and use information about customers to help us better understand the offers, promotions, and types of advertising that are most appealing to our customers. The information they collect is aggregated so it is not identifiable to a specific individual.

 _Children's data_  
While none of Commercialbank's web sites are directed towards children, we are committed to comply with applicable laws and requirements, such as the United States' Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

 _Privacy technology_  
Technology will increasingly help you to have more control over your personal information. It will also help organizations to manage their privacy practices and policies. As an information technology provider, Commercialbank actively supports the development of privacy technologies to help achieve these goals, and to help create greater trust and confidence in the way personal information is handled. Products and services are available which can help give you privacy protection while navigating the Web.

__Cookies, web beacons and other technologies__  
We sometimes collect anonymous information from visits to our sites to help us provide better customer service. For example, we keep track of the domains from which people visit and we also measure visitor activity on Commercialbank web sites, but we do so in ways that keep the information anonymous. This anonymous information is sometimes known as 'clickstream data.' Commercialbank or its analytic vendors may use this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better customer service.

Also, when we collect personal data from you in connection with a transaction we may extract some information about that transaction in an anonymous format and combine it with other anonymous information such as clickstream data. This anonymous information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patterns. None of this information is reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner, you can either disable your cookies or opt-out at the order or request page.

We collect the anonymous information we mentioned in the previous paragraphs through the use of various technologies, including one called "cookies". A cookie is an element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your system. Some Commercialbank pages use cookies, sent by Commercialbank or its third party vendors, or other technologies to better serve you when you return to the site. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to turn off cookies. If you do so, however, some areas of some sites may not function properly.

Some Commercialbank Web sites also use Web beacon technologies to better tailor those sites to provide better customer service. These 'Web beacons' are placed on a number of pages across Commercialbank Web sites. When a visitor accesses these pages, an anonymous notice of that visit is generated which may be processed by us or by our vendors. These Web beacons work in conjunction with cookies. If you don't want to associate your anonymous cookie information with your visits to these pages, you can set your browser to turn off cookies.

If you turn off cookies, web beacon technologies will still detect anonymous visits to these pages, but the notices they generate cannot be associated with other anonymous cookie information and are disregarded.

 _Business relationships_  
The Commercialbank site contains links to other Web sites. Commercialbank is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

 _Notification of Changes_  
This privacy statement was last updated on October 15 2002. A notice will be posted on our web site home page for 30 days whenever this privacy statement is changed.

 _Questions regarding this statement_  
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to the Commercialbank site coordinator for clarification or at Communications Department,   
Commercial Bank of Qatar (QSC)  
P.O Box 3232, Doha, Qatar

|   |  |   
---  
|    
---
